<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="xml"?>
<book xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <info>
        <title>DK Schema 2.0 Specification</title>
        <subtitle>Working Draft</subtitle>
        <!-- stripping this as don't want it to render im html version
        <author>
            
            <orgname>Penguin Group UK</orgname> 
            <address>  
                <city>London</city>
                <street>80 Strand</street>
                <postcode>WC2 0RL</postcode>
                <country>United Kingdom</country>
                <email>dk-schema@kode1100.com</email>
            </address>
            
        </author>
        <copyright>
            <year>2011</year>
        </copyright> -->
        
    </info>
 <chapter>
     <title>Common Schema</title>
     <section xml:id="usage">
         <title>When to use?</title>
         <para>Whenever possible use the common schema, called <phrase>dk-schema.rnc</phrase> to
                validate the files, variants such as cookery are authored separately but it is still
                possible to validate such variant using the common schema file.</para>
     </section>
        <section xml:id="s.attributes">
        <title>DK Common Attributes</title>
        <para><phrase role="attribute">xml:id</phrase> attribute is used to provide a unique identifier for a given block.</para>
        <para>DK Schema allows for a set of attributes that can be used anywhere in the XML structure.</para>
        <para>These attributes are <link xlink:href="http://www.docbook.org/tdg/common">Docbook common attributes</link> and DK specific attributes.</para>
        <para><phrase role="attribute">condition</phrase> and <phrase role="dk.attribute">cref</phrase> attributes are used for profiling (marking content for a specific use). Refer to <xref xlink:href="#s.profiling"/> for more details.</para>
        <para><phrase role="attribute">lat</phrase> and <phrase role="attribute">lon</phrase> are used to associate geocoding information. Refer to <xref xlink:href="#s.geo"/> for more details.</para>
        <para><phrase role="dk.attribute">rend</phrase> attribute is used to provide strictly presentational hints to the rendering system. Refer to <xref xlink:href="#s.emphasis"/> for more details.</para>
            <para><phrase role="dk.attribute">metaref</phrase> attribute is used to link to additional metadata about the subject. Refer to <xref xlink:href="#s.meta"/> for more details.</para>
            <para><phrase role="attribute">role</phrase> attribute is used to classify portions of the content. Refer to <xref xlink:href="#s.role"/> for more details.</para>
            <para><phrase role="attribute">linkend</phrase> attribute should be used whenever possible for linking between parts of the document in elements such as <phrase role="element">link</phrase> and <phrase role="element">xref</phrase>. In more advanced scenarios, such as linking to external documents it is possible to use <link xlink:href="http://google.com?q='xlink'">Xlink</link> specification and specifically <phrase role="attribute">xlink:href</phrase> attribute instead of <phrase role="attribute">linkend</phrase>.</para>    
        </section>
    
    
    <section xml:id="s.address">
        <title>Address elements</title>
        <para>The standard Docbook elements <phrase role="element">address</phrase> (and constituent elements - <phrase role="element">street</phrase>, <phrase role="element">city</phrase>, <phrase role="element">state</phrase>, <phrase role="element">country</phrase>, <phrase role="element">pob</phrase>, <phrase role="element">postcode</phrase>, <phrase role="element">otheraddr</phrase>) should be used.</para>
        <para>The Docbook elements (<phrase role="element">street</phrase>, <phrase role="element">city</phrase> etc) as well as additional elements: <phrase role="element">phone</phrase>, <phrase role="element">fax</phrase>, <phrase role="element">email</phrase> are allowed inside the <phrase role="element">address</phrase> wrapper.</para>
        <para>Where necessary, single, inline <phrase role="element">address</phrase> elements can be used, wrapped within an <phrase role="element">address</phrase> element</para>
        <para>In addition to the standard Docbook constraints, please follow these rules:</para>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem><para>Use <phrase role="element">otheraddr</phrase> to mark up the post box number.</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>Use <phrase role="element">pob</phrase> to indicate auxillary information about the address, such as the house name, or "last house on the left".</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>Use <phrase role="element">street</phrase> element to indicate street and house or flat number.Put street name and number together, the way it should be displayed in a given country, for example "34 Temple Grove" in the UK or "Roosevelta 4" in Poland. Avoid using abbreviated form such as "High st.", use the full name, for example "High Street"</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>Use <phrase role="element">city</phrase> element to indicate city, town, village, settlement. If necessary use <phrase role="attribute">metaref</phrase> attribute to indicate the accurate description of the type of the place.</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>Use <phrase role="element">state</phrase> element to indicate state, region, county, province, canton, territory and similar geographical distinctions. If necessary use <phrase role="attribute">metaref</phrase> attribute to indicate the accurate gographical description of the type of the place.</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>Use <phrase role="element">postcode</phrase> element to indicate postcode, zipcode or equivalent alphanumeric definition of an area. Avoid using dashes or characters that are not part of the post code itself. If necessary use <phrase role="attribute">metaref</phrase> attribute to indicate the type of the code, for example metaref="zipcode".</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>Use <phrase role="element">country</phrase> element to indicate the country of an address. If necessary use <phrase role="attribute">metaref</phrase> attribute with ISO-3166 alpha 2 for country classification, for example metaref="GB"</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>Use <phrase role="element">phone</phrase> element to indicate the telephone for a given address. If necessary use <phrase role="attribute">metaref</phrase> attribute with ISO-3166 alpha 2 to indicate country code, for example metaref="GB". Avoid including the country code in the number - this can be generated in the output programatically.</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>Use <phrase role="element">uri</phrase> element for markup if the place described also has an address on the Internet. Do not include the protocol prefix (http:// or http://) and avoid including the www. prefix, if the website works without it. See <xref linkend="s.xref"/> for more details on marking-up URIs.</para></listitem>
        </orderedlist>
        <para>If it is necessary to collect the address in the form "Address Line Number 1, Line 2" or to output it in the same form, map the line numbers to the semantically appropriate DK Schema elements for example <phrase role="element">street</phrase> or if the is no clear match, use <phrase role="element">otheraddr</phrase> and use XML document order to preserve the address Line numbering.</para>
        <para>In cases, where more detailed, or custom descriptions of address may be necessary, use additional <phrase role="element">phrase</phrase> elements with a <phrase role="attribute">role</phrase> attribute inside an <phrase role="element">address</phrase> or develop a taxonomy and use <phrase role="attribute">metaref</phrase> attribute instead of role.</para>
        <para>
            The following attributes from the Docbook v5.x Schema: <phrase role="attribute">continuation</phrase>, <phrase role="attribute">format</phrase>, <phrase role="attribute">linenumbering</phrase> are not allowed.
        </para>
        <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/address/address.xml">Example</link></para>
        <para role="image_link"><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/address/address.jpg">Example</link></para>
        
        
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="s.date">
        <title>Date</title>
        <para>Dates should be captured using a <phrase role="element">phrase</phrase> element, with
                a <phrase role="attribute">role="date"</phrase> attribute value. </para>
             <para>For date ranges, see <xref linkend="s.range"/>.</para>
            <para>For more descriptive tagging options see <xref linkend="s.meta"/></para>
       
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="s.directory">
        <title>Directory</title>
        <para>Content that contains a directory of contact addresses, further information, phone book listing etc. should be captured with a <phrase role="attribute">role</phrase> attribute indicating a directory entry container element.</para>
        <para>Use <phrase role="element">section</phrase> with a <phrase role="attribute">role="directory"</phrase> attribute if the directory exists as a top-level entry in the structure of the book or <phrase role="element">section</phrase> with a <phrase role="attribute">role="directory"</phrase> attribute if the directory exists below the chapter level.</para>
        <para>Individual entries should be captured using a block level element such as <phrase role="element">section</phrase> with a <phrase role="attribute">role="dir_entry"</phrase> attribute.</para>
        <para>Directory can be further subdivided using a block level element such as <phrase role="element">section</phrase> with a <phrase role="attribute">role="dir_section"</phrase> attribute.</para>
        <para><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/directory/directory.xml">Example</link></para>
        <para><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/directory/directory_Homeopathy.jpg">Example</link></para>
        <para>A directory listing containing referential type of information should be captured using <phrase role="element">section</phrase> elements with a <phrase role="attribute">role</phrase> attribute indicating a directory entry container element.</para>
        <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/directory/directory.xml">Example</link></para>
        <para role="image_link"><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/directory/directory_Homeopathy.jpg">Example</link></para>

        
    </section>
    
    
    
    <section xml:id="s.toc">
        <title>Table of Contents</title> 
        <para>Under normal circumstances, Table of Contents should not be captured by hand. Instead, the structure of the book must be captured using a hierarchy of parts, chapters and sections. The Table of Contents will be automatically generated from that.</para>
        <para>If there is a specific case where an alternative Table of Contents needs to be produced that does not reflect the hierarchy of the XML, use <phrase role="element">toc</phrase> element.</para>
        <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/toc/toc.xml">Example</link></para>
        <para role="image_link"><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/toc/contents.jpg">Example</link></para>
        
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="s.index">
        <title>Index</title> 
        <para>If it is desirable to auto-generate an index, individual terms may be marked-up at the point-of-reference in the text using the <phrase role="element">indexterm</phrase> element.</para>
        <para>Otherwise, capture the index using the <phrase role="element">index</phrase> element inside a <phrase role="element">book</phrase> or <phrase role="element">part</phrase> element.</para>
        <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/index/index.xml">Example</link></para>
        <para role="image_link"><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/index/index_ewc_tree.jpg">Example</link></para>
        
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="s.set">
        <title>Set element</title>
        <para><phrase role="element">Set</phrase> element is used to group books from one series to allow validation of crossreferences.</para>
        <para>In normal circumstances <phrase role="element">set</phrase> may not be used and <phrase role="element">book</phrase> should be used to capture a single title.</para>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="s.book">
        <title>Book element</title>
        <para><phrase role="element">Book</phrase> should be the default top-level (root) element for a title. </para>
        <para>The DK book model follows docbook specification, although it does not allow <phrase role="element">colophon</phrase> and <phrase role="element">bibliography</phrase>.</para>
        
        <para>A <phrase role="attribute">version</phrase> attribute must be used to indicate which version of the schema is being used (5 at the time of writing).</para>
        
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="s.frontmatter">
        <title>Frontmatter</title>
        <section xml:id="s.cover">
            <title>Book covers</title>
            <para>Use <phrase role="element">cover</phrase> element inside the <phrase role="element">info</phrase> block for the book to describe the cover.</para>
            <para>Usually this will point to an image on the cover, in which case use <phrase role="element">mediaobject</phrase>.</para>
            <para>Where two or more different covers are used for different outputs, use multiple <phrase role="element">cover</phrase> elements with the appropriate <phrase role="attribute">condition</phrase> attribute.</para>
            <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/frontmatter/TT_SANFRA-frontmatter.xml">Example</link></para>
        </section>
        
        
        <section xml:id="s.biblio">
            <title>Bibliographic information</title>
            <para>Where a book includes a bibliography, mark-up using simple structural elements as appropriate (e.g. <phrase role='element'>appendix</phrase> or <phrase role="element">article</phrase>) with a with a <phrase role="attribute">role="bibliography"</phrase> attribute value.</para>
            <para>To annotate bibliographic information associated with the whole book, use the following bibliographic elements inside the <phrase role="element">info</phrase> block:</para>
            
            <section xml:id="s.biblioid">
                <title><phrase role="element">biblioid</phrase></title>
                <para>Use <phrase role="element">biblioid</phrase> with attribute <phrase role="attribute">class</phrase> set to "ISBN" to indicate the ISBN number of the book.</para>
                <para>To capture multiple ISBN numbers for different editions of the book (such as printed vs ebook), use multiple <phrase role="element">biblioid</phrase> elements with <phrase role="attribute">condition</phrase> attribute and group the together using <phrase role="element">biblioset</phrase> element.</para>
                <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/frontmatter/TT_SANFRA-frontmatter.xml">Example</link></para>
            </section>
            <section xml:id="s.revhistory">
                <title>Revision history</title>
                <para>To capture the revision history of the printed book, use <phrase role="element">revhistory</phrase> element.</para>
            </section>
            
        </section>
        <section xml:id="s.author">
            <title>Authors, editors and publisher</title>
            <para>To capture the information about the main author, use a single <phrase role="element">author</phrase> element inside the <phrase role="element">info</phrase> block.</para>
            <para>To capture multiple authors, editors contributors etc, use multiple <phrase role="element">author</phrase> and <phrase role="element">editor</phrase> elements and group them together using <phrase role="element">authorgroup</phrase> element.</para>
            <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/frontmatter/TT_SANFRA-frontmatter.xml">Example</link></para>
        </section>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="s.appendix">
        <title>Appendices, copyright page, acknowledgments, inside covers</title>
        <para>Any front or back-matter book level construct that does not fit into the standard <phrase role="element">part</phrase> / <phrase role="element">chapter</phrase> / <phrase role="element">section</phrase> structure should be captured using the <phrase role="element">appendix</phrase> element.</para>
        <para>Use the <phrase role="attribute">role</phrase> attribute to indicate the type of content captured, for example acknowledgments (see <xref linkend="s.role"/>).</para>
        <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/frontmatter/TT_SANFRA-frontmatter.xml">Example</link></para>
    </section>
    
    
    
    <section xml:id="s.chapter">
        <title>Chapter</title>
        <para><phrase role="element">chapter</phrase> should be the default top-level book division for content that runs over more than a single spread. It may contain a number of <phrase role="element">section</phrase> elements, or nested <phrase role="element">section</phrase> elements if more granular division is required.</para>
        <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/chapter/chapter.xml">Example</link></para>
        <para role="image_link"><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/chapter/contents_animal.jpg">Example</link></para>
    </section>  
    
    
    <section xml:id="s.part">
        <title>Part elements</title>
        <para><phrase role="element">Part</phrase> elements are used to indicate parts of the <phrase role="element">book</phrase>. They should only be used when there are distinctive parts of the book above chapter level. If there is only one level of hierarchy, <phrase role="element">chapter</phrase> elements should be used.</para>
        <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/book_part/book.xml">Example</link></para>
        <para role="image_link"><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/book_part/contents_animal.jpg">Example</link></para>
        
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="s.article">
        <title>Article</title>
        <para><phrase role="element">Article</phrase> should only be used immediately below the <phrase role="element">part</phrase> or <phrase role="element">book</phrase> level, and for portions of information that can be used standalone.</para>
        <para>Article is sometimes equivalent to a page spread.</para>
        <para>Nested <phrase role="element">article</phrase> or an <phrase role="element">article</phrase> inside a <phrase role="element">chapter</phrase> is not allowed. If such a division is deemed to be helpful, use <phrase role="element">section</phrase> instead and apply the <phrase role="attrbiute">role</phrase> attribute with a value 'article'.</para>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="s.glossary">
        <title>Glossary</title>
        <para><phrase role="element">Glossary</phrase> would normally be used as a child of the <phrase role="element">book</phrase> element.</para>
        <para>If a glossary occurs at a lower level (such as <phrase role="element">chapter</phrase> or <phrase role='element'>article</phrase>), use <phrase role="element">glosslist</phrase>.</para>
        <para role="image_link"><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/glossary/glossary_1.jpg">Example</link></para>            
        <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/glossary/glossary-submarine.xml">Example</link></para>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="s.section">
        <title>Section elements</title>
        <para><phrase role="element">Section</phrase> elements are used to create logical subdivisions and to reflect the structure of the <phrase role="element">book</phrase>.</para>
        <para><phrase role="element">Section</phrase> elements can be nested. It may be helpful to use stylesheets (XSLT ot CSS) or XML editing tool functions to ensure that the nesting is correct.</para>
        <para>It not recommended to use section elements with an empty title but if a structural split is necessary and no appropriate title can be give, use empty <phrase role="element">title</phrase> element. This, among other things can impede the work tools such as PDF, ebook, TOC generation.</para>
        <para>The <phrase role="attribute">role</phrase> attribute can be used to specify functions of a <phrase role="element">section</phrase> (see <xref linkend="s.role"/>).</para>
        <para><phrase role="attribute">role="feature"</phrase> can be used to indicate standalone portions of information that can not be captured using <phrase role="element">article</phrase> or <phrase role="element">sidebar</phrase>.</para>
        <para><phrase role="attribute">role="entry"</phrase> can be used to capture blocks equivalent to reference book entries.</para>
        <para><phrase role="attribute">role="article"</phrase> can be used to capture blocks equivalent to standalone articles in a book.</para>
        <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/section/section.xml">Example</link></para>
        <para role="image_link"><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/section/contents_animal.jpg">Example</link></para>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="s.sidebar">
        <title>Sidebar</title>
        <para><phrase role="element">sidebar</phrase> should only be used to capture simple portions of information that are separated from the main flow of text.</para>
        <para><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/sidebar/sidebar.xml">Example</link></para>
        <para><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/sidebar/feature.jpg">Example</link></para>
        <para>In more complex scenarios, where additional structure needs to be captured, use <phrase role="element">section</phrase> with <phrase role="attribute">role="feature"</phrase> attribute value.</para>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="s.titleabbrev">
        <title>Title Abbreviations</title>
        <para>Use the <phrase role="element">titleabbrev</phrase> element in block constructs such as <phrase role="element">section</phrase> if there is a need to capture an abbreviated version of a title.</para> 
        <para>Note this should not be used in place of <phrase role="attribute">xreflabel</phrase> (see <xref linkend="s.xref"/>).</para>
        <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/titleabbrev/titleabbrev.xml">Example</link></para>
        <para role="image_link"><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/titleabbrev/titleabbrev.jpg">Example</link></para>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="s.xref">
        <title>Cross-references</title>
        <para>The <phrase role="element">xref</phrase> element with the <phrase role="attribute">linkend</phrase> attribute should be used to for internal document links and cross-references. This will allow the link text to be generated from the target element (usually from the title text).</para>
        <para>Cross-references should point to the block elements such as <phrase role="element">article</phrase> or <phrase role="element">section</phrase> and not their respective <phrase role="element">title</phrase> elements.</para>
        <para>If an alternative or abbreviated link text is needed, use <phrase role="attribute">xreflabel</phrase> attribute on the target element.</para>
        <para>See <link linkend="s.meta">metadata</link> section for instances where the content linked by a <phrase role="element">xref</phrase> should be meta-tagged.</para>
        <para>Use the <phrase role="element">link</phrase> element with the  <phrase role="attribute">linkend</phrase> attribute when the rendering of the cross-reference should not be generated.</para>
        <para>For external links (such as a website url) use <phrase role="element">link</phrase> with a <phrase role="attribute">xlink:href</phrase> attribute.</para>
        <para>If useful to mark-up a website url semantically, but render as a plain text string, use the <phrase role="element">uri</phrase> element.</para>
        <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/crossref/crossref.xml">Example</link></para>
        <para role="image_link"><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/crossref/xref.jpg">Example</link></para>
        <formalpara>
            <title>Cross-references to ranges</title>
            <para>Where a cross-reference points to a span of content that can not be naturallry wrapped in a structural element such as <phrase role="element">section</phrase>, use <phrase role="element">range</phrase> elements to delimit the span of content and cross-reference the start of that range. Follow <link linkend="s.range">range</link> specification to create such a range.</para>
            
        </formalpara>
        
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="s.footnote">
        <title>Footnotes</title>
        <para>To capture footnotes use <phrase role="element">footnote</phrase> element inline in the text.</para>
        <para>The whole content of the footnote should be captured within the <phrase role="element">footnote</phrase> element.</para>
        <para>The <phrase role="element">footnote</phrase> element usually generates a mark (a superscript symbol or number) at the place in the flow of the document in which it occurs. The body of the footnote is then presented elsewhere, typically at the bottom of the page.</para>
        <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/footnote/footnote.xml">Example</link></para>
        <para role="image_link"><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/footnote/footnote.jpg">Example</link></para>
        
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="s.fraction">
        <title>Mathematical formulas, fractions, ranges and units</title>
        <para><phrase role="element">informalequation</phrase> and <phrase role="element">mathphrase</phrase> element should be used to capture simple mathematical values, formulas, numbers, fractions, equations and similar numerical expressions. </para>
        <para><phrase role="attribute">Role</phrase> attribute on the <phrase role="element">mathphrase</phrase> can be used to indicate parts of the expression such as fraction.</para>
        <para>For non inline math, use <phrase role="element">equation</phrase> element</para>
        <para>For complex formulas use MathML or <phrase role="element">mediaobject</phrase> to provide verbatim rendering.</para>
        <para><phrase role="element">alt</phrase> element inside the <phrase role="element">equation</phrase> or <phrase role="element">inlineequation</phrase> can be used to indicate the most simple form of the expression.</para>
        <section xml:id="s.range">
            <title>Ranges</title>
            <para>Use <phrase role="element">range</phrase> element to indicate the beginning and the end of a range.</para>
            <para>Alternatively use <phrase role="element">phrase</phrase> element to indicate the beginning and the end of a small, inline range, for example <xref linkend="s.date"/> range.</para>
            <para>Use <phrase role="attribute">class="startofrange"</phrase> and <phrase role="attribute">xml:id</phrase> attribute to indicate the beginning of a range.</para>
            <para>Use <phrase role="attribute">class="endofrange"</phrase> and <phrase role="attribute">startref</phrase> attribute to point to the <phrase role="attribute">xml:id</phrase> of the start of a range and indicate the end of a range.</para>
            <para><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/fraction/unit.xml">Example</link></para>
            <para><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/metadata/entry_animal.jpg">Example</link></para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="s.units">
            <title>Units</title>
            <para>In the event that it is necessary to apply very granular tagging to
                numerical values (such as weights and measures), use <phrase role="element">phrase</phrase> element to isolate each value,
                and <phrase role="dk.attribute">metaref</phrase> attribute and a metadata preset item/group to define the standard unit of
                measurement.</para>
            <para>For example, units of measure as defined by International System of Units (SI) may
                be added as an item/group in metadata preset XML. </para>
            <para>Note it is not expected that such granular tagging will be the norm. Often it is
                better (and far-less labour intensive), to isolate these values programmatically
                (e.g. through a regular expression algorithm), than to tag each value upfront. </para>
            <para>See <xref linkend="s.meta"/> and <xref linkend="s.range"/>.</para>
            <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/fraction/unit.xml">Example</link></para>
            <para><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/metadata/entry_animal.jpg">Example</link></para>
        </section>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="s.presentation">
        <title>Highlighting, emphasis, page breaks and presentational markup</title>
        <para>DK-Schema is meant to be presentation neutral, so that the content can be repurposed to many outpus such as ebooks, audiobooks, apps etc.</para>
        <para>Therefore it is not receommended to be too prescriptive about the presentation of content - it makes the XML verbose and makes repurposing less flexible.</para>
        <para>In the justifiable cases, a limited set of presentational markup is allowed to hint the rendering systems as to how to display the content.</para>
        <section xml:id="s.rend">
            <title><phrase role="attribute">rend</phrase> attribute</title>
            <para>The <phrase role="attribute">rend</phrase> attribute can be used to give a hint to the rendering engine as to how the text may be displayed (e.g. bold or italic).</para>
            <para>The <phrase role="attribute">rend</phrase> is equivalent to HTML class attribute.</para>
            <para>Follow CSS3 W3C specification and use CSS3 selectors as available <phrase role="attribute">rend</phrase> atrrbitue values. Note that not all values will be recognised or uspported on all rendering platforms.</para>
            <para>The <phrase role="attribute">rend</phrase> attribute can contain multiple, space sparated values such as <phrase role="attribute">rend='bold italic break-after'</phrase></para>
        </section>
        
        <section xml:id="s.pagebreak"><title>Page breaks and line breaks</title>
        <para>It is not supported to put explicit page or line breaks in the DK-Schema.</para>
            <para>Wherever possible, use appropriate semantic structures such as <phrase role="element">section</phrase> or <phrase role="element">para</phrase> so that the rendering systems can infer the layout from the structure of the document.</para>
            <para>In cases, where the default behaviour has to be overriden, use <phrase role="attribute">rend</phrase> attribute and CSS selectors such as page-break-after to suggest the desired rendering behaviour.</para>    
        </section>
        <section xml:id="s.emphasis">
            <title>Emphasis</title>
            <para></para>
            <para>Use <phrase role="element">emphasis</phrase> element to capture text that should have a different visual representation.</para>
            
            <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/emphasis/emphasis.xml">Example</link></para>
            <para role="image_link"><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/emphasis/emphasis.jpg">Example</link></para>
        </section>
    </section>
    
    
   
    
    <section xml:id="s.lists">
        <title>Lists</title>
        <para>Care must be taken in choosing the most simple and appropriate list type.</para>
        <para><phrase role="element">simplelist</phrase> should be sufficient in majority of the cases. The <phrase role="attribute">type</phrase> attribute can be used to further specify the presenetation of the list.</para>
        <para><phrase role="element">itemizedlist</phrase> should normally be used for bulleted lists.</para>
        <para>A <phrase role="element">phrase</phrase> element can be used to highlight a heading or a keyword inside a list.</para>
        <para><phrase role="element">Variablelist</phrase> should only be used to represent a list of term definitions.</para>
        <para><phrase role="element">segmentedlists</phrase> should only be used as a simple alternative to represent lists or series of data and only in basic cases where there are no empty fields (cells) and there is a one to one mapping between every item in the segmented list and its associated heading.</para>
        <para>The following list types are allowed in DK-Schema:</para>
        
        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><phrase role="element">simplelist</phrase></term>
                <listitem><para>An undecorated list of single words or short phrases.</para></listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            
            <varlistentry>
                <term><phrase role="element">itemizedlist</phrase></term>
                <listitem><para>A list in which each entry is marked with a bullet or other dingbat.</para>
                <para>That bullet or dingbat can be specified via mark attribute that point to the URI of the image.</para></listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><phrase role="element">orderedlist</phrase></term>
                <listitem><para>A list in which each entry is marked with a sequentially incremented <phrase role="element">label</phrase>.</para>
                    <para>It possible to specify <phrase role="element">orderedlist</phrase> <phrase role="element">label</phrase> to be arabic, roman and alphabetic, using <phrase role="attribute">numeration</phrase> attribute.</para>
                    <para>The <phrase role="attribute">continuation</phrase> attribute can specify to continue, restart or inherit the numbering from previous or parent list.</para>
                    <para>For more details please refer to <link xlink:href="http://www.docbook.org/tdg5/en/html/orderedlist.html">The Definitive Guide Ordered List</link> page.</para></listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><phrase role="element"><phrase role="element">variablelist</phrase></phrase></term>
                <listitem><para>A list in which each entry is composed of a set of one or more terms and an associated description.</para></listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><phrase role="element">segmentedlist</phrase></term>
                <listitem><para>A segmented list, a list of sets of elements.</para></listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            
            
            
        </variablelist>
        
        <para role="image_link">
            <link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/lists/itemized_list_1.jpg">Example</link></para>
            <para><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/lists/itemized_list_2.png">Example</link></para>
            <para><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/lists/orderedlist.gif">Example</link></para>
            <para><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/lists/segmentedlist.gif">Example</link></para>
            <para><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/lists/simplelist.gif">Example</link></para>
            
            <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/lists/lists.xml">Example</link></para>
            
           
        
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="s.keys">
        
        <title>Keys</title>
        <para>A <phrase role="element">key</phrase> is a textual or a graphical list that is referred from another location in the document.</para>
        <para>To capture a <phrase role="element">key</phrase> use <phrase role="element">variablelist</phrase> with attribute <phrase role="attribute">role="key"</phrase>.</para>
        <para><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/key/key_fishbrain.xml">Example</link></para>
        <para>Attribute <phrase  role="attribute">xreflabel</phrase> can be used to define a title of the key (<phrase role="element">variablelist</phrase>) or the key entry (<phrase role="element">listitem</phrase>). If no value is specified, a default word "Key" may be rendered by the transformation toolkit in place of the <phrase role="element">xref</phrase>.</para>
        <para><phrase role="element">Variablelist</phrase> for key must have an xml:id attribute.</para>
        <para>All the <phrase role="element">varlistentry</phrase> elements must have xml:id attribute.</para>
        <para>If the <phrase role="element">key</phrase> lists graphics, use <phrase role="element">mediaobject</phrase> inside the <phrase role="element">listitem</phrase> to capture that, give that <phrase role="element">mediaobject</phrase> and <phrase role="attribute">xml:id</phrase> and link directly to that <phrase role="element">mediaobject</phrase>.</para>
        <para><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/key/key_encaqu.xml">Example</link></para>
        <para>The <phrase role="element">key</phrase> should be placed at the beginning of the relevant XML fragment, usually the beginning of a <phrase role="element">section</phrase> or a <phrase role="element">chapter</phrase> or <phrase role="element">mediaobject</phrase> <phrase role="element">caption</phrase>.</para>
        <para>To refer to a defined <phrase role="element">key</phrase> use <phrase role="element">xref</phrase> element with a <phrase role="attribute">role</phrase> attribute, so that custom processing can applied.</para>
        <para>Use <phrase role="attribute">role="keyref"</phrase> to produce a link to the key.</para>
        <para><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/key/key_brainweight.xml">Example</link></para>
        <para>Use <phrase role="element">role="key_include"</phrase> to include/render that key or
                key entry where the link is. </para>
            <para>In such case you need to verify the variablelist is allowed where you place the
                xref. You can chack that by simply adding the variablelist, validating and then
                removing the variablelist and replacing it with xref <phrase role="element"
                    >role="key_include"</phrase>.</para>
        <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/key/key_encaqu.xml">Example</link></para>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="s.graphics">
        <title>Graphics</title>
        
        <section xml:id="s.mediaobject">
            <title>Media Objects</title>
            <para>All media such as photos, graphs and the associated annotations, heads, and captions should be captured using <phrase role="element">mediaobject</phrase> element and its children.</para>
            <para><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/graphics/mediaobject-encaqu.xml">Example</link></para>
            <para><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/graphics/illustration_encaqu.jpg">Example</link></para>
            <para>If the graphic object must be displayed inline, use <phrase role="element">inlinemediobject</phrase>.</para>
            <para><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/graphics/inlinemediaobject.xml">Example</link></para>
            <para><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/graphics/inline_icon_iPod.jpg">Example</link></para>
            <para><phrase role="element">Textobject</phrase> can be used to provide a fallback text description of the object and any text that is not rendered along with the actual graphic media.</para>
            <para>Use <phrase role="element">caption</phrase> for the image captions and other text that needs to be displayed alongside the media.</para>
            <para>For images with callouts, see <xref linkend="s.callouts"/>.</para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="s.illustrationgroup">
            
            
            <title>Groups of illustrations</title>
            <para>To logically group media objects such as illustrations use <phrase role="element">figure</phrase>.</para>
            <para><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/graphics/mediaobject-encaqu.xml">Example</link></para>
            <para>If the group of illustrations does not have a <phrase role="element">title</phrase>, use <phrase role="element">informalfigure</phrase>.</para>
            <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/graphics/informalfigure.xml">Example</link></para>
            <para role="image_link"><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/graphics/BB_illust_group.png">Example</link></para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="s.callouts">

            <title>Callouts and annotated illustration</title>
             <para>For images with annotations use <phrase role="element">imageobjectco</phrase> inside the <phrase role="element">mediaobject</phrase> and <phrase role="element">calloutlist</phrase> with <phrase role="element">callout</phrase> elements inside.</para>  
            <para>The <phrase role="attribute">arearefs</phrase> attribute in a <phrase role="element">callout</phrase> element is mandatory to uniquely identify a <phrase role="element">callout</phrase>.</para>
            <para><phrase role="element">areaspec</phrase> is an optional element available for use recording the areas on a graphic that a <phrase role="element">callout</phrase> relates to.</para>
            <para> When an <phrase role="element">areaspec</phrase> is defined it will associate the <phrase role="element">callout</phrase> with an area of an image.</para>
            
            
            
            <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/graphics/butterfly.xml">Example</link></para>
            
            <para>Alternatively, where the XML fragment describing portions of the illustration can be used standalone, use separate <phrase role="element">section</phrase> elements, outside of the <phrase role="element">mediaobject</phrase> to describe that content and put crossreferences to those <phrase role="element">section</phrase> elements in the <phrase role="element">callout</phrase> construct using <phrase role="element">link</phrase> or <phrase role="element">xref</phrase>.</para>
            <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/graphics/callout-bird.xml">Example</link></para>
            <para role="image_link"><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/graphics/Bird_callout_Divided world.png">Example</link></para>
        </section>
        
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="s.procedure">
        <title>Procedure</title>
        <para>Use <phrase role="element">procedure</phrase> element to capture all lists where order is important, such as 'step by step', cooking instructions and other types of sequences.</para>
        <para>When the numbering needs to be preserved rather than generated, please use <phrase role="element">phrase</phrase> element with a <phrase role="attribute">role="stepnum"</phrase> to specify the glyph associated with the step.</para>
        <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/procedure/procedure-centrifuge.xml">Example</link></para>
        <para role="image_link"><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/procedure/procedure_centrifuge.png">Example</link></para>
        <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/procedure/procedure-animal.xml">Example</link></para>
        <para role="image_link"><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/procedure/Animal_illust_group.png">Example</link></para>
        <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/procedure/procedure.xml">Example</link></para>
        <para role="image_link"><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/procedure/stepbystep_survival.jpg">Example</link></para>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="s.phrase">
        <title>Phrase</title>
        <para>Where possible, use the best matching inline element to capture meaning; for instance <phrase role="element">foreignphrase</phrase> for latin words.</para>        
        <para>Where no useful element is present, the <phrase role="element">phrase</phrase> element and an appropriate <phrase role="attribute">role</phrase> attribute value can be used.</para>
        <para>It may be useful to combine <phrase role="element">phrase</phrase> with dk metadata attributes; see <link linkend="s.meta">metadata</link> section.</para>
        <para>The <phrase role="element">phrase</phrase> element may be used to indicate an inline heading or keywords.</para>        
    </section>
    
    
    
    <section xml:id="s.para">
        <title>Paragraphs</title>
        <para><phrase role="element">para</phrase> element is the default element to represent blocks of text.</para>
        <para>DK Schema <phrase role="element">para</phrase> element is equivalent to a Docbook <phrase role="element">simplepara</phrase> model.</para>
        <para><phrase role="element">para</phrase> should only contain text and inline formatting elements.</para>
        <para><phrase role="element">para</phrase> should not contain structural elements such as <phrase role="element">section</phrase>.</para>
        <para><phrase role="element">para</phrase> should not contain block level elements such as <phrase role="element">blockquote</phrase> and in such cases additional blocks should be captured outside of <phrase role="element">para</phrase> element.</para>
        
    </section>
    
    
    
    
    <section xml:id="s.formalpara">
        <title>Formal Paragraph</title>
        <para>A formal paragraph - <phrase role="element">formalpara</phrase> should be used to capture blocks of text with an inline <phrase role="element">title</phrase> or a heading.</para>
        <para><phrase role="element">formalpara</phrase> requires that both <phrase role="element">title</phrase> and <phrase role="element">para</phrase> elements are present and non-empty.</para>
        <para>In cases where both the <phrase role="element">title</phrase> and the <phrase role="element">para</phrase> are not always consistently present, a <phrase role="element">para</phrase> with a <phrase role="element">phrase</phrase> should be used to capture the content.</para>
        <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/formalpara/formalpara.xml">Example</link></para>
        <para role="image_link"><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/formalpara/list_item_phrase.jpg">Phrase Example</link></para>
        <para role="xml_link"><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/formalpara/list_item_formalpara.jpg">Formalpara Example</link></para>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="s.qandaset">
        <title>Questions and Answers (Q&amp;A)</title>
        <para>To handle sets of questions and answers, use Docbook <phrase role="element">qandaset</phrase> model.</para>
        <para>Use <phrase role="element">qandaentry</phrase> for each entry and <phrase role="element">question</phrase> and <phrase role="element">answer</phrase> respectively.</para>
        <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/qandaset/qandaset.xml">Example</link></para>
        <para role="image_link"><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/qandaset/qandaset.jpg">Phrase Example</link></para>
        
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="s.table">
        <title>Tables</title>
        <para>CALS Table format is used to capture any tabular data.</para>
        <para>CALS Table model allows for complex <phrase role="element">table</phrase> structures such as <phrase role="element">colspan</phrase> and <phrase role="element">rowspan</phrase> and it is easy to convert to alternative representations such as HTML Table or CSV.</para>
        <para><phrase role="element">Table</phrase> should only be used to capture actual tabular data such as statistics or similar two-dimensional data-representations.</para>
        <para><phrase role="element">Table</phrase> should not be used for presentational purposes only such as fixing layout issues.</para>
        <para>Use <phrase role="element">informaltable</phrase> if the table has no <phrase role="element">title</phrase> that is visible and should be rendered or normal <phrase role="element">table</phrase> element for a <phrase role="element">table</phrase> with a <phrase role="element">title</phrase>.</para>
        <para>Use <phrase role="element">tgroup</phrase> to specify number of columns and default formatting.</para>
        <para><phrase role="element">Colspec</phrase> is optional and is used to specify the width, sequence etc of a column. It is
            required if you're defining column spans. If you are declaring a <phrase role="element">colspec</phrase>, do so for all
            columns and you have to provide <phrase role="element">colname</phrase> for all columns.</para>
        <para>Use <phrase role="attribute">namest</phrase> and <phrase role="attribute">namend</phrase> attributes on <phrase role="element">entry</phrase> element to specify cells spanning multiple
            columns.</para>
        <para>Use <phrase role="attribute">morerows</phrase> attribute to specify vertical spans.</para>
        <para>For all other cases please refer to <link xlink:href="http://www.docbook.org/tdg/en/html/table.html">TDG section on CALS</link> and <link xlink:href="http://www.oasis-open.org/specs/tm9502.html">CALS Table Model Specification</link>.</para>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="s.quote">
        <title>Quotations</title>
        <para>Use <phrase role="element">quote</phrase> element to capture inline quotations, citations and similar text structures.</para>
        <para>Use <phrase role="element">blockquote</phrase> to capture quotations that are logically separate from the rest of the text and should be rendered as a separate block.</para>
        <para>Where quotation is the first element in a <phrase role="element">chapter</phrase>, <phrase role="element">article</phrase> or a similar division, this is usally an <phrase role="element">epigraph</phrase> and should be captured as an <phrase role="element">epigraph</phrase> element.</para>
        <para>Do not include literal quotation characters in quotes. Their appeareance can be controlled when publishing via XSL or otherwise.</para>
        <para role="xml_link"><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/blockquote/blockquote_epigraph.xml">Example</link></para>
        <para role="image_link"><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/blockquote/epigraph.jpg">Example</link></para>
        
    </section>
    
    
    
    <section xml:id="s.profiling">
        <title>Profiling</title>
        <para>Profiling is a technique to conditionally filter out portions of XML.</para>        
        <para>Use <phrase role="attribute">condition</phrase> attribute on an element to mark it for profiling.</para>
        <para>This is done by applying a <phrase role="attribute">condition</phrase> attribute at the lowest possible level.</para>
        <para>If there is no suitable element to apply the profiling, wrap the XML or text fragment in a <phrase role="element">phrase</phrase> element, to keep it at the lowest level. </para>
        <para>Every element that has profiling applied (<phrase role="attribute">condition</phrase> attribute) needs to have a <phrase role="attribute">cref</phrase> attribute to uniquely identify that XML portion.</para>
        <para>If two blocks of XML represent the same content for different outputs, they need to have the same <phrase role="attribute">cref</phrase> attribute value.</para>
        <para>Nesting of profiling should be avoided in general to prevent confusing results. Nesting for the same type of condition will not work.</para>
        <para>For example if a whole sentence is marked as print only (<phrase role="attribute">condition="prt"</phrase>) and a word inside as digital, the digital part will never show up in digital output as the whole sentence is profiled out. </para>
        
        <para>Profiling should be used sparsely  and only where necessary as it duplicates the XML and can have unforeseen consequences.</para>
        <para>Linking: Conditional content might get stripped upon profiling. if possible links should point to parent element that isn't profiled. If that's not possible, stylesheet should translate links to the equivalent elements by matching on <phrase role="attribute">cref</phrase> values.</para>
        <para>Appropriate use cases include:</para>
        <simplelist>
            
            <member>Output specific content: print vs digital. In this case point links and xrefs to digital variant or parent element.</member>
            <member>Imperial vs Metric measurements. In this case, it can be decided to include only Metric </member>
            
        </simplelist>
        
    </section>
     
     <section xml:id="s.rolevsmeta">
         <title>Using <phrase role="attribute">rend</phrase>, <phrase role="attribute">role</phrase> and <phrase role="attribute">metaref</phrase> attributes</title>
         <variablelist>
             <varlistentry>
                 <term><phrase role="attribute">rend</phrase></term>
                 <listitem><para>Attribute <phrase role="attribute">rend</phrase> should be used for clearly presentational purposes (equivalent to HMTL class attribute)  free form and can include multiple (space separated) values</para></listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             <varlistentry>
                 <term><phrase role="attribute">role</phrase></term>
                 <listitem><para>Attribute <phrase role="attribute">role</phrase> should be used for semantic mark-up and re-defines or adds to the semantics of the element to which it is applied.</para>
                     <para> Only one value is allowed, and DK-Schema does not maintain an enumerated list of allowed values in the schema.</para>
                     <para> It is assumed that in most cases more detailed values can entirely replace less detailed values without loss of meaning  e.g. the default value <phrase role="attribute">role='feature'</phrase> can be replaced with <phrase role="attribute">role='human impact'</phrase> and serve the same purpose. </para>
                     <para>In the event that an element must have more that one semantic term associated with it <phrase role="attribute">metaref</phrase> and meta.xml categorisation must be used.</para></listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             <varlistentry>
                 <term><phrase role="attribute">metaref</phrase></term>
                 <listitem><para>to be used to associate phrases or blocks with terms described in a term/subject classification taxonomy, which is itself defined in meta.xml.</para>
                     <para>meta.xml classification can be created on request, but this needs to go through the schema working group who will advise on its design.</para></listitem>
             </varlistentry>
         </variablelist>
     </section>
     
     <section xml:id="s.role">
         <title><phrase role="attribute">Role</phrase> attribute</title>
         <para>The <phrase role="attribute">role</phrase> attribute may be used re-define the semantics of any docbook element, this may occur on block and inline elements</para>       
         <para>It may be useful to combine <phrase role="attribute">role</phrase> with dk metadata attributes; see <link linkend="s.meta">metadata</link> section.</para>
         <para>The enumeration of <phrase role="attribute">role</phrase> values and rules for their usage will be validated with a DK schematron.</para>
         <para>Currently the following role values are allowed:</para>
         <variablelist>
          
             <varlistentry xml:id="s.article.role">
                 <term>article</term>
                 <listitem><para>Used on <phrase role="element">section</phrase> below the <phrase role="element">chapter</phrase> level element to indicate content that is standalone.</para>
                     <para>For high-level chunks of content you can still use <phrase role="element">article </phrase> element.</para>
                     <para>This constructs is used instead of a dedicated article element, to simplify processing and make XML more consistent.</para>
                     <para>Typically, if the XML is sourced from a printed book, <phrase role="element">section</phrase> with role article is equivalent to a two-page spread in a book.</para>
                 </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             <varlistentry xml:id="s.feature.role">
                 <term>feature</term>
                 <listitem><para>To be used on <phrase role="element">section</phrase> element to indicate a small chunk of content that is standalone, potentially resuable and related to the subject of the parent section/topic..</para></listitem>
             </varlistentry >
             <varlistentry xml:id="s.directory.role">
                    <term>directory</term>
                    <listitem>
                        <para/>
                        <para>Content that contains a directory of contact addresses, further
                            information, phone book listing etc. should be captured with a <phrase
                                role="attribute">role</phrase> attribute indicating a directory
                            entry container element. See <xref linkend="s.directory"/> for more details.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
             <varlistentry xml:id="s.dir_entry.role">
                 <term>dir_entry</term>
                 <listitem><para>Used to indicate individual directory entries. See <xref linkend="s.directory"/></para></listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             <varlistentry xml:id="s.dir_section.role">
                 <term>dir_section</term>
                 <listitem><para>Used to group and subdivide directory entries. See <xref linkend="s.directory"/></para></listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             <varlistentry xml:id="s.illustration.role">
                 <term>illustration</term>
                 <listitem>
                     <para>Used on <phrase role="element">section</phrase> below the <phrase role="element">chapter</phrase> level element to wrap standalone illustration that do not belong to any particular section of text..</para>
                     <para>See <xref linkend="s.graphics"/> for more information</para>
                     <para>Such section must not have a title of it's own - used textobject of the child mediaobject.</para>
                 </listitem>
                     
             </varlistentry>
             <varlistentry xml:id="s.intro.role">
                 <term>intro</term>
                 <listitem>
                     <para>Used on the first <phrase role="element">para</phrase> element of a given <phrase role="element">section</phrase>.</para>
                     <para>Use this to indicate introductory paragraph of a given chunk of content.</para>
                 </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             <varlistentry xml:id="s.key.role">
                 <term>intro</term>
                 <listitem>
                     <para>See <xref linkend="s.keys"/></para>
                 </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             <varlistentry xml:id="s.key_include.role">
                 <term>intro</term>
                 <listitem>
                     <para>See <xref linkend="s.keys"/></para>
                 </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             <varlistentry xml:id="s.leadin.role">
                 <term>leadin</term>
                 <listitem>
                     <para>Used on the first <phrase role="element">phrase</phrase> element of a given <phrase role="element">para</phrase>.</para>
                     <para>Use this to indicate introductory sentence of a paragraph.</para>
                 </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             <varlistentry xml:id="s.map.role">
                 <term>map</term>
                 <listitem>
                     <para>Used on <phrase role="element">section</phrase> below the <phrase role="element">chapter</phrase> level element to wrap standalone maps that do not belong to any particular section of text.</para>
                     <para>See <xref linkend="s.graphics"/> for more information</para>
                     <para>Such section must not have a title of it's own - use textobject of the child mediaobject.</para>
                 </listitem>
                 
             </varlistentry>
             <varlistentry xml:id="s.map_ref.role">
                 <term>map_ref</term>
                 <listitem>
                     <para>Use on linking elements such as <phrase role="element">xref</phrase> and <phrase role="element">link</phrase>.</para>
                     <para>Use this to indicate that this a particular type of link that is pointing to an area of a map.</para>
                 </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             <varlistentry xml:id="s.note.role">
                 <term>note</term>
                 <listitem>
                     <para>Used on the <phrase role="element">para</phrase> element.</para>
                     <para>Use this to indicate that this portion of text is a note.</para>
                 </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             <varlistentry xml:id="s.pagenumber.role">
                 <term>pagenumber</term>
                 <listitem>
                     <para>Use only on the <phrase role="element">phrase</phrase> element that is part of an index.</para>
                     <para>Use this to point index entries to patricular page numbers in a printed book.</para>
                 </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             <varlistentry xml:id="s.runningHead.role">
                 <term>runningHead</term>
                 <listitem>
                     <para>Use only on the first <phrase role="element">para</phrase> element in a section.</para>
                     <para>By default the tile of the current chapter and section will be the running head. Use this to specify a different running head.</para>
                 </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             <varlistentry xml:id="s.timeline.role">
                 <term>timeline</term>
                 <listitem>
                     <para>Use only on the <phrase role="element">section</phrase> element to indicate a timeline.</para>
                     <para>Use this role to indicate a chunk of content that spans a period of time.</para>
                 </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             <varlistentry xml:id="s.timeline_entry.role">
                 <term>timeline_entry</term>
                 <listitem>
                     <para>Use only on the <phrase role="element">section</phrase> or <phrase role="element">para</phrase> element to indicate an entry in a timeline.</para>
                     
                 </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
             <varlistentry xml:id="s.timeline_description.role">
                 <term>timeline_description</term>
                 <listitem>
                     <para>Use only on the  <phrase role="element">para</phrase> element to indicate that the paragraphs is a description of an entry in a timeline.</para>
                     
                 </listitem>
             </varlistentry>
         </variablelist>
         <para>If you need to introduce a new role value, double check that the appropriate role or meta values is not already defined and contact the DK-Schema core team to update the validation tools.</para>
     </section>  
    
    <section xml:id="s.meta">
        <title>Metadata Presets</title>
        <para>A custom functionality has been introduced in DK Schema to allow straightforward classification and tagging of chunks of content using predefined presets.</para>
        <para>Meta classification can be applied in the following ways:</para>
        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><phrase role="element">meta</phrase> element in an <phrase role="element">info</phrase> block</term>
                <listitem><para>This is the recommended behaviour. This means that the metadata will apply the the whole block.</para>
                    <para>Multiple <phrase role="element">meta</phrase> elements are allowed.</para>
                    <para>Use <phrase role="attribute">metaref</phrase> and point to the <phrase role="attribute">xml:id</phrase> in the meta classification defined in the <phrase role="filename">meta.xml</phrase></para></listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><phrase role="attribute">metaref</phrase> attrbute on any element</term>
                <listitem><para>If the meta classification needs to be applied for a small portion of XML use <phrase role="attribute">metaref</phrase> attribute on any element.</para>
                    <para>If there is no suitable element, use <phrase role="element">phrase</phrase> element with a <phrase role="attribute">metaref</phrase> attribute.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
                <term><phrase role="attribute">metaref</phrase> on a <phrase role="element">xref</phrase> element</term>
                <listitem><para>If a <phrase role="element">xref</phrase> element is used to generate an image or text found in a key (see <link linkend="s.keys">keys</link>), and it is desirable to further classify the key information with metadata, the <phrase role="attribute">metaref</phrase> attribute must be applied to the <phrase role="element">xref</phrase> element.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            
            
        </variablelist>
        <para>The descriptions of the available and allowed meta values are in the <link linkend="metafile">Meta XML file</link>. </para>
        <para><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/metadata/metadata-animal.xml">Example</link></para>
        <para><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/metadata/entry_animal.jpg">Example</link></para>

        
        <section xml:id="metafile">
            <title>Meta XML file</title>
            <para>The meta classification presets are stored in the <phrase role="filename">meta.xml</phrase> and can be extended by adhering to the <phrase role="filename">meta.rnc</phrase> RelaxNG schema.</para>
            <para>The <phrase role="filename">meta.xml</phrase> file has a number of <phrase role="element">item</phrase> and <phrase role="element">group</phrase> elements that define a given classification.</para>
            <para>At minimum every <phrase role="element">item</phrase> and <phrase role="element">group</phrase> needs to have a unique <phrase role="attribute">xml:id</phrase> attribute that will be used to refer to that classification from individual XML files as well as a <phrase role="element">name</phrase>.</para>
            <para><phrase role="element">description</phrase> helps by giving more details about a given classification.</para>
            <para><phrase role="element">source</phrase> identifies the origin of classification, for example: "Rough Guides", "Navteq", "Natural History DB" etc..</para>
            
        </section>
      
    </section>
    
    
    
    <section xml:id="s.geo">
        <title>Geocoding</title>
        <para>In order to associate geographic location with a portion of XML <phrase role="attribute">lat</phrase> and <phrase role="attribute">long</phrase> attributes are allowed on most elements.</para>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="custom.dk">
        <title>Customization</title>
        
        <para>From the very beginning, one of the goals of DK-Schema has been
            that users should be able to produce customizations that are either
            subsets of extensions of common Dk-Schema.</para>
        
        
        
        <para>In DK-Schema v2, we hope to take advantage of RELAX NGs more
            robust design (and it's lack of pernicious determinism rules) to make
            customization easier.</para>
        
        <para>Three schema design patterns in the underlying DocBook v5 design get us most of the way there.</para>
        
        <section xml:id="db.s.patnames">
            <title>Logical Groupings</title>
            
            <para>DocBook elements, particularly the inlines, can be divided into
                broad classes: general purpose, technical, error-related, operating-system
                related, bibliographic, publishing, etc. In DocBook V5.0, these are collected
                together in named patterns.</para>
            
            <para>To add a new inline, <literal>endpoint</literal> for example,
                to the list of technical inlines, one need only extend the appropriate
                pattern. If an element should appear in several classes, they can all
                be extended in the same way:</para>
            
            <programlisting>db.technical.inlines |= endpoint
                db.programming.inlines |= endpoint
                db.os.inlines |= endpoint</programlisting>
            
            <para>Much the same concept was used in DocBook V4.x, where instead of
                patterns we had parameter entities. However, the constraints of DTD
                validation severely limit the circumstances under which an element can
                appear twice in a content model. That meant that adding an element to
                one parameter entity might make it an error to add it to another. Such
                constraints do not exist in RELAX NG which greatly simplifies the
                customization.</para>
        </section>
        
        <section xml:id="db.s.elemdefs">
            <title>Element Definitions</title>
            
            <para>Each element in DocBook V5.0 is defined by its own pattern. To
                change the content model of an element, only that pattern need be
                redefined. To remove an element from DocBook, that pattern can be
                redefined as <quote><literal>notAllowed</literal></quote>.</para>
            
        </section>
        
        <section xml:id="db.s.attrdefs">
            <title>Attribute Definitions</title>
            
            <para>Each attribute list in DocBook V5.0 is defined by its own
                pattern. To change the list of attributes available on an element,
                only that pattern need be redefined. To remove all the attributes,
                that pattern can be redefined as
                <quote><literal>empty</literal></quote>.</para>
            
        </section>
    </section>
    
 </chapter>
 <chapter>
     <title>Phrase Book</title>
     <section xml:id="pb_usage">
         <title>When to use?</title>
         <para>Phrase Book variant should be used for all phrasebooks, dictionaries and multilingual content.</para>
         <para>It allows typical Common DK-Schema content plus phrase book specific content based on TEI P5 dictionary model.</para>
         <para>If no specific phrasebook element exists, use equivalent Common DK-Schema / Docbook element, for example <phrase role="element">quote</phrase>.</para>
         <para>To clarify the usage the following should be established:
         <procedure>
             <step><para>What is the native language of the audience?</para>
             <para>This language should be considered local.</para>
                 <para>Any portions of phrase entries in the local language should normally be captured inside <xref xlink:href="#s.sense"/> structure and its children such as <xref xlink:href="#s.def"/> regardless of the order of appearance.</para></step>
             <step><para>What is the language the audience doesn't understand?</para>
                 <para>This language should be considered foreign.</para>
                 <para>Any portions of phrase entries in the foreign language should normally be captured inside <xref xlink:href="#s.form"/>structure and its children such as <xref xlink:href="#s.orth"/> regardless of the order of appearance.</para></step>
         </procedure>
         </para>
         <para>For example in a book for English readers with foreign phrases in German, all German phrases should be captured inside <xref xlink:href="#s.form"/>structure and its children and their English equivalents inside <xref xlink:href="#s.sense"/> structure and its children.</para>
         <para role="external_link">For more information on TEI p5 architecture please go to: <link role="reference" xlink:href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/DI.html">TEI Reference</link></para>
         <para><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/phrasebook/rg_phrasebook.xml">Example</link></para>
         <para><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/phrasebook/RGPB_GERMAN_b.gif">Example</link></para>
     </section>
     
     <section xml:id="s.phrase_entry">
         <title>Phrase Entry</title>
         <para>This is the main block and wrapper for a phrase entry.</para>
         <para>A typical phrase entry should ideally consist of at least one portion in the source language using the <phrase role="element">form</phrase> element and at least one portion in target language using  the <phrase role="element">sense</phrase> element.</para>
         <para><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/phrasebook/EW_ChinesePhraseBook.xml">Example</link></para>
         <para><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/phrasebook/15MinutesChinese.gif">Example</link></para>
         
     </section>
     
     <section xml:id="s.phrase_xref">
     <title>Crossreferencing phrase entries</title>
         <para>Whenever there is a crossreference inside a <phrase role="element">phrase_entry</phrase> element, use standard Docbook linking elements: <xref xlink:href="#s.xref"/></para>
         <para>Use <phrase role="element">xref</phrase> for links to other portions of XML and <phrase role="element">link</phrase> to point ot non-resolvable destination such as pages or parts of an image.</para>
         <para>A <phrase role="attribute">role</phrase> attribute value of <phrase role="attribute">role="phrase_entry_include"</phrase> can be used to specify that the link phrase entry or its portion should be copied and included inline.</para>
         <para>A <phrase role="attribute">role</phrase> attribute value of <phrase role="attribute">role="phrase_entry_ref"</phrase> can be used to specify that the link phrase entry or its portion should be referenced and a hyperlink created.</para>
     </section>
     
     <section xml:id="s.form">
         <title>Phrase Form</title>
         <para><phrase role="element">Form</phrase> element groups all the information on the written and spoken forms of one headword.</para>
         <para><phrase role="element">Form</phrase> should be used to capture content foreign to the audience, for more explanation go to: <xref xlink:href="#s.phrase_entry"/></para>
         <para role="external_link">For more information on TEI p5 form please go to: <link role="reference" xlink:href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/ref-form.html">TEI Form Reference</link></para>
         <para><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/phrasebook/EW_ChinesePhraseBook.xml">Example</link></para>
         <para><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/phrasebook/15MinutesChinese.gif">Example</link></para>
         
     </section>
     <section xml:id="s.inline_phrase_entry">
         <title>Inline Phrase Entry</title>
         <para>This is the inline version of a phrase entry.</para>
         <para>See <xref xlink:href="#s.phrase_entry"/> for a full definition.</para>
         <para>The inline version of the phrase entry is to be used inside blocks such as <xref xlink:href="#s.para"/> or tables and the processing systems will by default not introduce any newlines or formatting.</para>
         <para><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/phrasebook/EW_ChinesePhraseBook.xml">Example</link></para>
         <para><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/phrasebook/15MinutesChinese.gif">Example</link></para>
         
     </section>
     
     <section xml:id="s.sense">
         <title>Phrase Sense</title>
         
         <para><phrase role="element">Sense</phrase> element groups together all information relating to one word sense in a dictionary entry, for example definitions, examples, and translation equivalents.</para>
         <para><phrase role="element">Form</phrase> should be used to capture content local to the audience, for more explanation go to: <xref xlink:href="#s.phrase_entry"/></para>
         <para>Whenever possible use <phrase role="element">def</phrase> to include the definition or the translation of the phrase.</para>
         <para role="external_link">For more information on TEI p5 sense please go to: <link role="reference" xlink:href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/ref-sense.html">TEI Sense Reference</link></para>
         <para><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/phrasebook/EW_ChinesePhraseBook.xml">Example</link></para>
         <para><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/phrasebook/15MinutesChinese.gif">Example</link></para>
         
     </section>
     
     <section xml:id="s.def">
         <title>Phrase Definition</title>
         <para><phrase role="element">Def</phrase> element contains definition text in a dictionary entry.</para>
         <para>Whenever possible use <phrase role="element">def</phrase> inside <phrase role="element">sense</phrase> element to include the definition or the translation of the phrase.</para>
         <para role="external_link">For more information on TEI p5 def please go to: <link role="reference" xlink:href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/ref-def.html">TEI Def Reference</link></para>
         <para><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/phrasebook/EW_ChinesePhraseBook.xml">Example</link></para>
         <para><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/phrasebook/15MinutesChinese.gif">Example</link></para>
         
     </section>
     
     <section xml:id="s.usg">
         <title>Phrase Usage</title>
         <para><phrase role="element">Usg</phrase> element contains usage or an example of a phrase text in an entry.</para>
         <para>Whenever possible use <phrase role="element">usg</phrase> inside <phrase role="element">sense</phrase> element to include the usage of the phrase.</para>
         <para role="external_link">For more information on TEI p5 usg please go to: <link role="reference" xlink:href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/ref-usg.html">TEI Usg Reference</link></para>
         <para><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/phrasebook/rg_phrasebook.xml">Example</link></para>
         <para><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/phrasebook/RGPB_GERMAN_b.gif">Example</link></para>
         
     </section>
     
     <section xml:id="s.orth">
         <title>Phrase Ortographic Form</title>
         <para><phrase role="element">Orth</phrase> gives the orthographic form of a dictionary headword or a phrase.</para>
         <para>Use <phrase role="element">orth</phrase> to capture the main form of the phrase in the original or source language.</para>
         <para>Whenever possible use <phrase role="element">orth</phrase> inside <phrase role="element">form</phrase> element.</para>
         <para role="external_link">For more information on TEI p5 orth please go to: <link role="reference" xlink:href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/ref-orth.html">TEI Orth Reference</link></para>
         <para><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/phrasebook/EW_ChinesePhraseBook.xml">Example</link></para>
         <para><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/phrasebook/15MinutesChinese.gif">Example</link></para>
         
     </section>
     
     <section xml:id="s.pron">
         <title>Phrase Pronounciation</title>
         <para><phrase role="element">Pron</phrase> contains the pronunciation(s) of the word.</para>
         <para>Whenever possible use <phrase role="element">pron</phrase> inside <phrase role="element">form</phrase> element.</para>
         <para role="external_link">For more information on TEI p5 pron please go to: <link role="reference" xlink:href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/ref-pron.html">TEI Pron Reference</link></para>
         <para><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/phrasebook/EW_ChinesePhraseBook.xml">Example</link></para>
         <para><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/phrasebook/15MinutesChinese.gif">Example</link></para>
         
     </section>
     
     <section xml:id="s.gramGrp">
         <title>Grammatical Classification</title>
         <para>Every phrase entry can be classified in the context of part of speech, number and gender. This classification should only be applied once in a given <phrase role="element">Phrase_entry</phrase> element.</para>
         <para>The classification should be grouped under <phrase role="element">gramGrp</phrase> element.</para>
         <para>The predefined classifications are:
         <simplelist>
             <member><phrase role="element">partofspeech</phrase></member>
             <member><phrase role="element">phrase_number</phrase></member>
             <member><phrase role="element">phrase_gender</phrase></member>
         </simplelist></para>
         <para>If necssary further classification can be specified by using <phrase role="element">phrase</phrase> with a <phrase role="attribute">role</phrase> attribute inside a <phrase role="element">gramGrp</phrase> element.</para>
         <para><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/phrasebook/rg_phrasebook.xml">Example</link></para>
         <para><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/phrasebook/RGPB_GERMAN_b.gif">Example</link></para>
     </section>
     
 </chapter>   
 
 <chapter>
     <title>Cookery</title>
     <section xml:id="cookery_usage">
         <title>Using Cookery Module</title>
         <para>
            DK Schema Cookery variant should be used to capture any book containing recipies.
         </para>
         <para>Typicaly, each recipe should be captured using <phrase role="element">recipe</phrase>.</para>
         <para><phrase role="element">Recipe</phrase> needs to have a <phrase role="element">title</phrase> and details about the recipe itself, such as:</para>
         <simplelist>
             <member><phrase role="element">ingredients</phrase></member>
             <member><phrase role="element">nutrition</phrase></member>
             <member><phrase role="element">preparation</phrase></member>
         </simplelist>
         <para>Capture any additional information such as serving size or preparation time using <phrase role="attribute">metaref</phrase> or <xref xlink:href="#s.keys"/>.</para>
     </section>
     <section xml:id="s.ingredients">
         <title>Ingredients</title>
         
         <para>A block containing a listing of ingredients used in a recipe.</para>
         <para>Identify each individual ingredient using <phrase role="attribute">role="ingredient"</phrase> attribute.</para>
         <para>Use <phrase role="attribute">metaref</phrase> attribute to identify units of measurement, see <xref xlink:href="#s.units"/> for more information.</para>
         <para>Use <xref xlink:href="#s.profiling"/> to distinguish between imperial and metric units.</para>
         <para><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/cookery/cookery-COOEXP.xml">Example</link></para>
         <para><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/cookery/cookery-COOEXP.png">Example</link></para>
     </section>
     <section xml:id="s.nutrition">
         <title>Nutrition</title>
         <para>Whenever possible, capture the nutritional information about the recipe and its ingredients, such as calories count, amount of fat, sodium, etc.</para>
         <para>If possible, wrap all nutrition information in a <phrase role="element">nutrition</phrase> element.</para>
         <para>Identify each individual nutritional ingredient using <phrase role="attribute">role="nutrition"</phrase>  attribute and <phrase role="attribute">metaref</phrase> attribute from "nutrition" meta group.</para>
         <para><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/cookery/cookery-COOEXP.xml">Example</link></para>
         <para><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/cookery/cookery-COOEXP.png">Example</link></para>
     </section>
     <section xml:id="s.preparation">
         <title>Preparation</title>
         <para><phrase role="element">Preparation</phrase> is the block for capturing the actual procedure of meal or recipe preparation, divided into steps.</para>
         <para>An individual prepration step should be captured using <phrase role="element">step</phrase> element. If it is necessary to explicitly indicate the step number, use the <phrase role="attribute">stepnum</phrase> attribute, otherwise the numbering will be generated automatically.</para>
         <para><link role="sample" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/samples/cookery/cookery-COOEXP.xml">Example</link></para>
         <para><link role="screenshot" xlink:href="http://dk-schema.googlecode.com/hg/screenshots/cookery/cookery-COOEXP.png">Example</link></para>
     </section>
 </chapter>
 <chapter xml:id="s.travel">
     <title>Travel</title>
     <section xml:id="s.travel_usage">
         <title>Tagging DK Travel content</title>
         <para>Typically, it should be possible to mark travel content using common DK-Schema. Additional layers of information can be added using <xref linkend="s.meta"/> for metadata, and, when necessary <phrase role="attribute">rend</phrase> for presentational information.</para>
         <para>Specifically, it should be done as follows:</para>
         <procedure>
             <title>Marking up DK Travel content</title>
             <step><title>Create high-level structure</title>
             <para>Use standard Docbook / DK-schema elements to create the desired structure of the document - parts, chapters, section for traditional book structure.</para>
             <para>If using topic-based authoring, create individual topics first and then assemble them together into a final structure, using Docbook Assembly mechanism.</para></step>
             <step><title>Create inline markup</title>
             <para>Mark up inline elements using a combination of standard Docbook elements and custom DK role attribute values to highlight specific, smaller chunks of content such as notes, features, etc.</para></step>
             <step><title>Apply Travel Metadata</title>
                 <para>To indicate particular chunks of content use <phrase role="element">meta</phrase> element (for block elements such as sections or topics) in the <phrase role="element">info</phrase> block.</para>
                 <para>For smaller, inline chunks such as as phrases use <phrase role="attribute">metaref</phrase> attribute.</para>
                 <para>The descriptions of the available and allowed meta values are in the <link linkend="metafile">Meta XML file</link>. </para>
             </step>
             <step>
                 <title>(Optional) Add presentational information</title>
                 <para>When absolutely necessary to satisfy project or product requirements, apply additional, presentation-specific information using <xref linkend="s.rend"/>.</para>
                 <para>This is not recommended as it may make the production of future projects more difficult.</para>
             </step>
         </procedure>
         <para></para>
     </section>
 </chapter>   
    <appendix xml:id="changes">
        <title>Revision History</title>
        <section xml:id="dk.ver2.0">
            <title>DK Schema Version 2.0</title>
            <para>This is the new version of the schema based on Docbook v5.x Publisher Subcommittee draft and it focuses on good interoperability with the Core Docbook schema.</para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="dk.ver1.0">
            <title>DK Schema Version 1.0</title>
            <para>This is the intial version of the schema based on: Docbook v4.x DTD, TEI, CALS and other industry standards</para>
        </section>
    </appendix>    
</book>
