<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://kode1100.com/dk/dk-schema/relaxng/dk-schema.rnc"?>
<book xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0"
    xml:id="TT_SANFRA">

    <info>
        <title>DK Eyewitness Top 10 Travel Guides San Francisco</title>
        <cover condition="prt">
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="print_cover.jpg"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </cover>
        <cover condition="dig">
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="digital_cover.jpg"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </cover>
        <publisher>
            <publishername>Dorling kindersley Limited</publishername>
            <address>
                <city>London</city>
                <street>80 Strand</street>
                <postcode>WC2R 0RL</postcode>
                <country>United Kingdom</country>
                <otheraddr role="website">www.dk.com</otheraddr>
            </address>
        </publisher>
        <authorgroup>
            <!-- authors can be grouped together -->
            <author role="main">
                <personname>
                    <firstname>Jeffrey</firstname>
                    <surname>Kennedy</surname>
                </personname>
            </author>
            <editor>
                <personname>
                    <firstname>Zoë</firstname>
                    <surname>Ross</surname>
                </personname>
            </editor>
        </authorgroup>
        <titleabbrev>TT</titleabbrev>
        <!-- can be used to conjure a unique ID used in epub OPF file -->
        <biblioset>
            <biblioid class="isbn" condition="prt">9781405348348</biblioid>
            <!-- to indicate ISBN of the printed book-->
            <biblioid class="isbn" condition="dig">9781405333559</biblioid>
            <!-- isbn for the epub -->
            <bibliosource class="isbn">9781405348348</bibliosource>
            <!-- to indicate the edition of the book that the epub has been sourced from -->
            <revhistory>
                <revision>
                    <date>2004</date>
                </revision>
                <revision>
                    <date>2006</date>
                </revision>
                <revision>
                    <date>2007</date>
                </revision>
                <revision>
                    <date>2008</date>
                </revision>
                <revision>
                    <date>2009</date>
                </revision>
                <revision>
                    <date>2010</date>
                </revision>

            </revhistory>

        </biblioset>
    </info>
    <part xml:id="TT_SANFRA006-079SANFRA">
        <title>San Francisco's Top 10</title>
        <chapter role="article" xml:id="TT_SANFRA006-007SANFRA">
            <title>San Francisco’s Highlights</title>
            <para role="intro" xml:id="TT_SANFRA006SANFRA_011">San Franciscans will, rather
                candidly, admit that they are the most fortunate people on earth, the occasional
                earthquake notwithstanding; and most visitors, after a few days of taking in the
                sights and sounds of this magnificent city, will agree. Ask anyone who has been here
                and they will tell you it’s their favorite US city. The geographical setting evokes
                so much emotional drama, the light seems clearer, the colors more vivid, the
                cultural diversity of the ethnic neighborhoods so captivating and inviting, that
                it’s a place almost everyone can fall in love with at first sight.</para>
        </chapter>
    </part>
    <appendix role="copyright">
        <title>Copyright</title>
        <para>Produced by Sargasso Media Ltd, London Reproduced by Colourscan, Singapore Printed and
            bound by South China Printing Co. Ltd., China First published in Great Britain in 2003
            by Dorling Kindersley Limited 80 Strand, London WC2R 0RL A Penguin Company Reprinted
            with revisions 2004, 2006, 2007, 2008, 2009, 2010 Copyright 2003, 2010 © Dorling
            Kindersley Limited, London All rights reserved. No part of this publication may be
            reproduced, stored in a retrieval system, or transmitted in any form or by any means,
            electronic, mechanical, photocopying, recording or otherwise, without the prior written
            permission of the copyright owner. A CIP catalogue record is available from the British
            Library ISBN 978-1-40534-834-8 Within each Top 10 list in this book, no hierarchy of
            quality or popularity is implied. All 10 are, in the editor’s opinion, of roughly equal
            merit. Floors are referred to throughout in accordance with American usage; ie. the
            “first floor” is at ground level.</para>
    </appendix>
    <appendix role="acknowledgments">
        <title>Acknowledgments</title>
        <section>
            <title>Main Contributors</title>
            <para>Native San Franciscan Jeffrey Kennedy now lives mainly in Italy and Spain. A
                graduate of Stanford University, he spends his time producing, writing and acting.
                He is also co-author of Top 10 Rome and author of Top 10 Mallorca and Top 10 Miami
                &quot; The Keys.</para>
            <para>Produced by Sargasso Media Ltd, London</para>
            <para>Editorial Director Zoë Ross Art Editor Janis Utton Picture Research Helen Stallion
                Proofreader Stewart J Wild Indexer Hilary Bird Editorial Assistance Tracy Becker
                Main Photographer Robert Vente Additional Photography Trevor Hill, Neil Lukas,
                Andrew McKinney, Rough Guides/Angus Oborn, Dan Rubin Illustrator chrisorr.com Fact
                Checkers Dan Rubin, AnneLise Sorensen</para>
            <para> For Dorling Kindersley Publishing Managers Ian Midson, Scarlett O’Hara Publisher
                Douglas Amrine Revisions Coordinators Rose Hudson, Mani Ramaswamy, Ros Walford, Hugo
                Wilkinson Assistant Revisions Coordinators Mary Ormandy, Pollyanna Poulter Senior
                Cartographic Editor Casper Morris DTP Jason Little Production Melanie Dowland
                Picture Librarian David Saldanha </para>

        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Additional Design and Editorial Assistance</title>
            <para>Sherry Collins, Conrad Van Dyk, Nicola Erdpresser, Claire Jones, Jude Ledger, Sam
                Merrell, Pete Quinlan, Karen Villabona</para>
            <formalpara>
                <title>Maps</title>
                <para>DK India: Managing Editor Aruna Ghose; Senior Cartographer Uma Bhattacharya;
                    Cartographic Researcher Suresh Kumar.</para>
            </formalpara>
            <formalpara>
                <title>Special Assistance</title>
                <para>The author would like to thank the following people for their assistance:
                    Patricia Perez-Arce and Ed, Sonal Bhatt, Bruce and Celeste Joki, Margaret Casey
                    and Mark Trahan, Robert Vente, Angela Jackson, Sandy Barnes, Harriet and Rick
                    Lehrbaum, Paul Brown, Phyllis Butler, Nini Dibble, Jolie Chain, Helen Craddick,
                    Vivian Deuschl, Marr Goodrum, and Isabelle Lejano.</para>
            </formalpara>
            <section>
                <title>Picture Credits</title>
                <para>t-top, tl-top left; tlc-top left center; tc-top center; tr-top right; cla-
                    center left above; ca-center above; cra-center right above; cl-center left;
                    c-center; cr-center right; clb-center left below; cb-center below; crb-center
                    right below; bl- bottom left, b-bottom; bc-bottom center; bcl-bottom center
                    left; br- bottom right; d-detail. Every effort has been made to trace the
                    copyright holders of images, and we apologize in advance for any unintentional
                    omissions. We would be pleased to insert the appropriate acknowledgments in any
                    subsequent edition of this publication. The publishers would like to thank the
                    following individuals, companies and picture libraries for their kind permission
                    to reproduce their photographs:</para>
                <para> ABSINTHE BRASSERIE &quot; BAR: 105tl; ALAMY IMAGES: Jim Gold- stein 40tl; ANA
                    MANDARA; 97tl. BAMBUDDHALOUNGE.COM: 70tl; BANCROFT LIBRARY, BERKELEY UNIVERSITY:
                    36tr; BRIAN BIGGS: 120tr. CABLE CAR MUSEUM: 11b; CALI- FORNIA ACADEMY OF SCIEN-
                    CES: 22b; Dong Lin 22tl, 22tr, 23br, 23tr; CAMPTON PLACE HOTEL: 114tl; THE CLIFT
                    HOTEL: Ian Schrager Hotels, Nikolas Koerno: 114tr; CORBIS: 1, 4–5, 8cl, 9, 10b,
                    12–13, 14–15, 16tl, 16b, 17c, 17b, 27c, 34t, 36tl, 37tr, 37br, 39, 40tr, 52tl,
                    52tr, 54tl, 54tr, 54b, 55r, 74b, 76tr, 78tl, 78tr, 79t, 80–81, 86–7, 102–03,
                    118–19, 130–31; COST PLUS WORLD MARKET: 96tr. DE YOUNG MUSEUM: Mark Darley 21c.
                    ENCHANTED CRYSTAL: photo by David J Landry 104tl; EXECUTIVE SUITES: 149tl;
                    Courtesy of the FINE ARTS MUSEUM OF SAN FRAN-CISCO: 114tl; FREY NOR- RIS
                    GALLERY: 42tl; GETTY IM- AGES: Ronald Martinez 73r; HOUSERSTOCK: Jan Butchofsky
                    – Houser 18t; Dave G Houser 15cr, 18–19, 75tl; THE LARK CREEK INN: 129tl;
                    TERRENCE MC- CARTHY: 56b; SEAN MORIARTY: 74tr; MUSEUM OF CRAFT &quot; FOLK ART:
                    Baby Frog 2001, blown and sand-carved glass, 11 x 103⁄4 x 8 inches Archie Noise
                    Cat photo Lee Fatheree 42b. NOVA BAR AND RESTAURANT: 66tr. Courtesy of OAKLAND
                    MUSEUM OF CALIFORNIA: 126tc, 126tr. PINK CLUB: Christian Horan Photography 71tl.
                    REDFERNS: David Redfern 54tc; REX FEATURES: 37cl, 53tl; RON- ALD GRANT ARCHIVE:
                    MGM 53tr; Paramount Pictures 16tr; Warner Brothers 53br. Collection of the SAN
                    FRANCISCO MUSEUM OF MODERN ART: Cali- fornia Artist, 1982 © Estate of Robert
                    Arneson/DACS London/ VAGA, New York, 2006 27t; Michael Jackson and Bubbles, 1988
                    Jeff Koons 27bl; SAN FRAN- CISCO ZOO: Jason Langer 114c. TABLESPOON: 3tr. ROBERT
                    VENTE: 20b, 32c, 32b, 33t, 34tr, 35t, 61r, 72b, 74tl, 148tl, 149. YANK SING:
                    91tl; JERRY YULSMAN: 52b. For jacket credits see Contents page All other images
                    are © Dorling Kindersley. For further information see: www.dkimages.com. </para>
            </section>

        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Special Editions of DK Travel Guides</title>
            <para>DK Travel Guides can be purchased in bulk quantities at discounted prices for use
                in promotions or as premiums. We are also able to offer special editions and
                personalized jackets, corporate imprints, and excerpts from all of our books,
                tailored specifically to meet your own needs. To find out more, please contact: (in
                the US) <email>specialsales@dk.com</email> (in the UK)
                    <email>travelspecialsales@uk.dk.com</email> (in Canada) DK Special Sales at
                    <email>general@tourmaline.ca</email> (in Australia)
                    <email>business.development@pearson.com.au</email></para>
        </section>
    </appendix>

</book>
